Paulin Fansi

Manchester, Lancashire, M27

Mobile: +447830258662 Email: <u>pfansi76@gmail.com</u> LinkedIn: <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/paulin-fansi-2956a7ba/</u>

| GitHub: https://github.com/pfansi

| Portfolio: https://pfansi.github.io/react-portfolio-app/

Personal Profile

Full stack Web developer with more than 5 years background experience in ecommerce. I successfully launched an ebay and amazon shop with a starting capital of £500 and we have now passed a combined sales figures of £100 000/year.

I successfully completed BS honours in web Systems development in the past. I am a lifelong student who embraces the digital world . I have knowledge in a variety of scripting languages such as Javascript , debugging processes and also multimedia web tools. I am capable of efficiently coding web applications with user experience in mind . I am a hard worker with attention to details and a team player. I am seeking the opportunity to learn more and accommodate myself with more complex web applications.

Key Skills

Technical Skills:

Programming Languages: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Jquery, Json, PHP **Applications:** Tailswincss, Bootstrap, Wordpress, REST API,Github, Mongodb, Express, Handelbars.js, React.js, MERN Stack, Mysql, Apollo GraphQL, Node.js, OOP, Photoshop, Adobe PremierPro, Camtasia, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Audio and Video Editing, Canva, Google Analytics, Google Adwords, Mailchimp, Zenstores.

Professional Skills:

- Bilingual in French both orally and written.
- Entrepreneurial and proactive strong drive and keen business mind.
- Brand, SEO, product and logistics knowledge.
- Critical thinker strong analytical skills; accurate and probing.

Projects

Group Project: Media Streamer

Github: https://github.com/pfansi/media-streamer

Deployed App: https://pfansi.github.io/media-streamer

- It is an application that will generate random movies or books based on a selected genre/category. It is taking away the frustration of jumping to several streaming platforms to find something you like to entertain yourself.
- Role: Worked on researching appropriate server side API, designing the user interface and refactoring javascript code files.
- **Tools Utilised:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JSON, Google Books API, tMBD APi, Streaming Availability API, TailwindCss Framework, Figma.

Group Project: Team Task Manager

Github: https://github.com/AidKool/team-task-manager

Deployed App: https://teamtask-manager.herokuapp.com/login

- This Project is about developing a Team Task Manager application using MVC (Model-View-Controller) technique that will allow a manager and employees to allocate tasks.
- **Role:** Contributed to the front end application design(Figma, HTML, CSS). Implemented functionalities for the login, logout and Project pages, both at the front and back end.
- **Tools Utilised:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JSON, Handlebars, Sequelize ORM, Express, MySQL, Node.js, Figma.

Team Project: Track My Move

Github: https://github.com/Allan-Ngwenya/track-my-move

Deployed App: https://track-my-move-backup.herokuapp.com/login

- This is a MERN stack with GraphQL application which allows users to keep track of their property purchase. The user keeps on track of this process by the help of a roadmap.
- Role: Created the logo, and the application front page. Added client side react components.
 implemented the roadmap functionality using Material-UI. I contributed to creating the application
 GraphQL Schemas, TypeDefs & Resolvers files and linked them to the MongoBD database.
 Contributed to coding the Node.js backend files.
- Tools Utilised: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, MongoDB, Apollo GraphQL, Heroku, Node.js.

Education & Qualifications

Full Stack Javascript Developer Certificate: University of Manchester, Manchester, UK (2022) 24-weeks intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Jquery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, Mysql, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & React.js.

BS Honours Web Systems Development: Edge Hill University, St Helens, UK (2010-2013)

A 3 years Program that focussed on learning: Web and multimedia development, Digital and Interactive Design, Search Engine Optimization, Web Content Management, Audio and Video Editing.

NVQ Level3 ICT : The Manchester College, Manchester, UK (2009-2010)

A one year Program that focuses on learning Information technology tools and creative multimedia applications.

Work Experience

Managing Director - Comput Services LTD, Manchester, UK May 2014 - Present

- Building content management systems for small businesses using Wordpress.
- Creating leaflets and business cards using Photoshop and Canva.
- Providing video and audio editing service using Adobe Premiere Pro and Camtasia.
- Providing search engine optimization advice using Google Analytics and Adwords.
- Managing a retail business on platforms such as Ebay and amazon.
- Providing branding advice and implementing free email marketing solutions such as Mailchimp.
- Proactively and reactively assisting customers with queries, complaints, and purchases.
- Supervising and training virtual assistants.
- Implementing Logistics tools such as Zenstores to other companies to increase performance.

Receptionist - Exclusafe LTD, Manchester, UK

May 2008 – July 2015

- Receptionist task and customer service support to building residents.
- Checked in people into buildings and gave out security passes and patrolled building sites.

Interests & Hobbies

I like to maintain a healthy lifestyle by jogging on a regular basis. My other passions are travelling, MMA and football.

References on Request